
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<title>About Islam on Truth about Islam</title>
	<link href="http://islamtruth.org/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="http://islamtruth.org/"/>
	<generator uri="https://gohugo.io/" version=".Hugo.Version">Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<updated>2018-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>http://islamtruth.org/</id>
	<author>
		<name>Mustafa Khan</name>
		<email>mustafa@islamtruth.org</email>
	</author>
  <entry>
	<title>History</title>
    <link href="http://islamtruth.org/islam/history/"/>
	<id>http://islamtruth.org/islam/history/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[


<p>Where did Islam come from? That is, indeed, a good question. And a difficult
one to answer. <strong>There are <a href="https://www.opendemocracy.net/faith-europe_islam/mohammed_3866.jsp">barely any sources</a> from
the early time of Islam</strong>, but we do know a lot more about what happened after
that.</p>

<h2 id="early-history">Early History</h2>

<p>The history, as presented by muslims, is that <strong>Islam originated in the early
7th century by a man known as Muhammad</strong>. He claims to have experienced an
angelic visitation, which had instructed him to become the last prophet
(of Islam). His utterances after that have been recorded in a book known
as the <em>Qur&rsquo;an</em>.</p>

<p>Due to the lack of evidence around the early history of Islam, we don&rsquo;t know
much about what really happened then. We can be fairly certain that <strong>a man
named Mohammed <a href="https://ask.ismailignosis.com/article/53-how-do-we-know-prophet-muhammad-actually-existed">did live</a></strong>, but we don&rsquo;t know what he was up to.
After his death, Islam was in it&rsquo;s infancy and <a href="https://www.rnw.org/archive/evidence-says-muhammad-existed">still developing</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://islamtruth.org/resource/movies/#islam-the-untold-story-2012">Islam: The Untold Story</a> is an interesting documentary that
explores the roots of Islam from a historical (rather than a theological)
perspective.</p>

<h2 id="golden-age">Golden Age</h2>

<p>When we think about the Arabs, we inevitably think about the golden age, the
height of the intellectual achievment of the now Islamic world. But how did
they get there? In two words, violence and tolerance.</p>

<div class="columns is-centered">
    <div class="column is-11">
        

<div >
  <iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/fDAT98eEN5Q"  allowfullscreen frameborder="0" title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
 </div>


    </div>
</div>


<!-- 
<div >
  <iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/vIGSNRCTkQI"  allowfullscreen frameborder="0" title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
 </div>
 -->

<h2 id="inventions">Inventions</h2>

<p>While today&rsquo;s age is dominated by inventions from the west, it hasn&rsquo;t
always been like this. There was a time when we were savages, only after
the <a href="http://www.columbia.edu/acis/ets/CCREAD/etscc/kant.html">Age of Enlightenment</a> was it that Europe really
took off as an intellectual powerhouse.</p>

<p>While there are undoubtedly some inventions made by the Islamic world,
many of them are, <em>sans evidence</em>, <strong>falsely attributed to Muslims</strong>.</p>

<div class="columns is-centered">
    <div class="column is-11">
        
<div class="columns">
    
<div class="column is-4">
    
<h6 class="has-text-success  has-text-weight-semibold  has-text-centered ">True Inventions</h6>

<div class="is-size-7 has-text-justified ">
    <p>The <strong>hookah</strong> is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hookah">a device</a> used to smoke <strong>shisha</strong>, a form of tobacco.</p>

<p>Hospitals in the islamic world accepted people with mental illnesses, giving rise
to the first <strong>mental institute</strong> in the world.</p>

<p><strong>Mercuric chloride</strong> was invented to disinfect wounds. Not used anymore due to
high toxicity.</p>

<p>The Ottoman empire military had the first recorded <strong>marching band</strong>.</p>

<p>The use of <strong>frequency analysis</strong>, a simple method of counting recurrences of
characters to read the primitive <a href="https://cryptii.com/caesar-cipher">Caesar
ciphers</a>, was first documented by an Arab.</p>

</div>


</div>

<div class="column is-4">
    
<h6 class="has-text-warning  has-text-weight-semibold  has-text-centered ">Unverified</h6>

<div class="is-size-7 has-text-justified ">
    <p><strong>Coffee</strong> was, according to the legend, invented in an Abyssinian
monastery, but the first recorded use was in Yemen.</p>

<p>Despite claims that the first <strong>fountain pen</strong> was developed for an Egyptian
emperor, the first recorded use was much later.</p>

</div>


</div>

<div class="column is-4">
    
<h6 class="has-text-danger  has-text-weight-semibold  has-text-centered ">False Claims</h6>

<div class="is-size-7 has-text-justified ">
    <p><strong>Arab numerals</strong> and the concept of <strong>zero</strong> were invented
by the Hindus.</p>

<p><strong>Algorithms</strong> were invented and used <a href="http://cs-exhibitions.uni-klu.ac.at/index.php?id=193">long before</a> the establishment
of Islam.</p>

<p><strong>Flight</strong> (more like gliding) was invented by the Chinese, with
the <a href="https://www.uh.edu/engines/epi340.htm">first recorded flight</a> in the 6th century.</p>

<p>The earliest known <strong>lenses</strong> predate Islam by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/History_of_optics">at least one millenium</a>,
and the earliest research on <strong>optics</strong> was in ancient India, <a href="http://www.benvr.net/technology/historyofoptics/">followed by
ancient Greek and Romans</a>.</p>

<p>Making <strong>gunpowder</strong> and using it for rockets was <a href="https://quatr.us/china/gunpowder-ancient-china.htm">invented by the Chinese</a>.</p>

<p><strong>Gardens</strong> have a history going back much before Islam was ever
mentioned.</p>

</div>


</div>


</div>


    </div>
</div>


<p>While the advances in science from the Islamic world may seem
modest compared to those from the ancient Romans, Greek or
Hindus, these are still significant. <strong>It is the cumulative efforts
of all those that came before us that brought us to where we
are now</strong>. We must not forget that.</p>

]]></content>
	
  </entry>
	
  <entry>
	<title>Movies</title>
    <link href="http://islamtruth.org/resource/movies/"/>
	<id>http://islamtruth.org/resource/movies/</id>
    <published>2018-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[


<p>Unfortunately, in developed, wester nations, people don&rsquo;t really
know much about Islam. This is a problem, because it means that
most people will have a knowledge of Islam that stems from either
Islamic preachers, which do not present a complete and accurate
picture, or from the news, which doesn&rsquo;t represent Islam as a
whole.</p>

<p>However, there have been a few people who have set out to
document Islamic facts, whether they relate to the early history
or to the current state of the religion and it&rsquo;s followers.</p>

<p>Here I present a collection of movies that I have watched myself
and found of highly educational value. Please do keep in mind
that you must be critical of anything you watch or read on the
Internet, regardless of what your position on things is.</p>

<h2 id="islam-the-untold-story-2012">Islam: The Untold Story (2012)</h2>

<div class="columns is-centered">
    <div class="column is-11">
        

<div >
  <iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/79051482"  webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe>
 </div>


    </div>
</div>


<p>Muslims have their own story about how and when Islam came to
be. But there is not a single piece of historical evidence to
back up this story &ndash; in fact, some evidence suggests that the
early history of Islam was entirely different from what many
people believe.</p>

<p>This documentary explores the history of Islam from a fact-based
rather than a faith-based perspective. What do we actually know?
What can we tell with certainty?</p>

<h3 id="on-the-web">On the Web</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt2402438/">IMDB: Islam: The Untold Story</a></li>
</ul>

<h2 id="this-is-what-winning-looks-like-2013">This is What Winning Looks Like (2013)</h2>

<div class="columns is-centered">
    <div class="column is-11">
        

<div >
  <iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/Ja5Q75hf6QI"  allowfullscreen frameborder="0" title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
 </div>


    </div>
</div>


<p>While the previous documentary was all about the early history of
Islam, this is the very opposite to that. VICE presents the current
state of things in Afghanistan, a country plagued by a religious-
extremist group (the Taliban), which has been exascerbated by
American involvement.</p>

<p>While there are a lot of documentaries about Islamic countries
and their current warfare out there, this is probably the most
shocking.</p>

<h3 id="on-the-web-1">On the Web</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/05/13/this-is-what-winning-looks-like_n_3268079.html">Huffington Post: ‘This Is What Winning Looks Like’: Ben Anderson Reports For Vice On The War In Afghanistan And Afghan Security Forces</a></li>
<li><a href="https://sofrep.com/50024/documentary-winning-looks-like/">SOFREP: Afghanistan documentary: ‘This is what winning looks like’</a></li>
<li><a href="https://kyleorton1991.wordpress.com/2014/05/22/film-review-this-is-what-winning-looks-like-2013-by-ben-anderson/">Film Review: This Is What Winning Looks Like (2013) by Ben Anderson</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/ppa4a8/this-is-what-winning-looks-like-part-1">VICE News: This Is What Winning Looks Like</a></li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/This_Is_What_Winning_Looks_Like">Wikipedia: This Is What Winning Looks Like</a></li>
</ul>

<h2 id="my-brother-the-islamist-my-brother-the-islamist-imdb-2011"><a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt1899251/">My Brother the Islamist</a> (2011)</h2>

<div class="columns is-centered">
    <div class="column is-11">
        
<div >
    <iframe frameborder="0"  src="//www.dailymotion.com/embed/video/x2kw7bs" allowfullscreen allow="autoplay"></iframe>
</div>


    </div>
</div>


<p>If after watching the VICE documentary, you believe that this is
not related to anything at all in the west, then this movie will
blow your mind.</p>

<p>It tells the sad story of Richard Dart, who falls prey into the
narrative of extremist islamic organisations in the UK. His
stepbrother, Robb Leech, follows him around, interviewing him
and the people around him on their newfound belief.</p>

<h3 id="on-the-web-2">On the Web</h3>

<ul>
<li>IMDB: <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt1899251/">My Brother the Islamist (2011)</a></li>
<li>BBC Programme: <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b010758h">My Brother the Islamist</a></li>
<li>Wikipedia: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Brother_the_Islamist">My Brother the Islamist</a></li>
<li>Independent: <a href="https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/crime/my-brother-the-islamist-richard-darts-extremist-beliefs-laid-bare-in-tv-documentary-8587897.html">My Brother the Islamist: Richard Dart&rsquo;s extremist beliefs laid bare in TV documentary</a></li>
<li>BBC three blog: <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/blogs/bbcthree/2011/04/my-brother-the-islamist.shtml">My Brother The Islamist: Dealing with the shock and hurt</a></li>
<li>Kanopy: <a href="https://www.kanopy.com/product/my-brother-terrorist">Watch &lsquo;My Brother the Islamist&rsquo;</a> for free if you are a member of a Library</li>
<li>The Guardian: <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2014/oct/22/brother-jihadi-terrorist-society-extremism">My brother wanted to be a jihadi – and society is creating many more like him</a></li>
</ul>

<h2 id="my-brother-the-terrorist-my-brother-the-terrorist-imdb-2014"><a href="my-brother-the-terrorist-imdb">My Brother the Terrorist</a> (2014)</h2>

<div class="columns is-centered">
    <div class="column is-11">
        
<div >
    <iframe frameborder="0"  src="//www.dailymotion.com/embed/video/x2g3owf" allowfullscreen allow="autoplay"></iframe>
</div>


    </div>
</div>


<p>In 2014, Robb Leech followed the documentary up with a sequel,
<a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt3676596/">My Brother the Terrorist</a>. This
highlights the even more shocking story as his stepbrother is
arrested for conspiracy to commit</p>

<h3 id="on-the-web-3">On the Web</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt3676596/">my-brother-the-terrorist-imdb</a></li>
<li>[my-brother-the-islamist-daily-mail]</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="raving-iran-raving-iran-imdb-2016"><a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt5945286/">Raving Iran</a> (2016)</h2>

<div class="columns is-centered">
    <div class="column is-11">
        

<div >
  <iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/lDX-zseHpdU"  allowfullscreen frameborder="0" title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
 </div>


    </div>
</div>


<p>German-Iranian cooperation. A movie between Iran and Austria about two
aspiring musicians fighting against an islamist regieme, being able to
flee.</p>

<h2 id="jihad-a-story-of-others-jihad-others-imdb-2015"><a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt4736576/">JIHAD: A Story of Others</a> (2015)</h2>


<div >
  <iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/9HKgowHRZ1c"  allowfullscreen frameborder="0" title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
 </div>


<h2 id="islam-s-non-believers-islam-non-believers-imdb-2016"><a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt6121442/">Islam&rsquo;s Non-Believers</a> (2016)</h2>


<div >
  <iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/rjVhjbLy2qE"  allowfullscreen frameborder="0" title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
 </div>


]]></content>
	
  </entry>
	
  <entry>
	<title>Mustafa</title>
    <link href="http://islamtruth.org/about/mustafa/"/>
	<id>http://islamtruth.org/about/mustafa/</id>
    <published>2018-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>Hey, I&rsquo;m Mustafa and I&rsquo;m the author behind all of the content (except for the
images and videos) of everything you can see on this website.</p>

<p>I have personally struggled with Islam and not believing. I consider myself an
agnostic, because I have grown up to doubt the things people try to convince me
of.</p>

<p>You can live your live bein naïve, or you can wake up and realize the truth,
that people will always try to influence you. In this modern age we are
confronted with adertisments. Governments have (in the past and to some extent,
today) created propaganda to try to influence people to be obedient. In the
same spirit, religions try to convince us &ndash; to try to get us to follow them.</p>

<p>Why is it that everyone wants us? In the end, it is all about power.  Companies
have the most transparent motives, as they want us to buy their products. They
want us to give out money to them. Governments need the support of their
people, especially during times of war.  And as the power of a religion is
measures in the number and piety of it&rsquo;s followers, gaining new people is
essential. In any case, it&rsquo;s always about power.</p>

<p>Survival in this age is all about being intelligent and having a sharp mind to
recognize these things. Being sceptic of the things people tell you, and
learning to recognize what their true intentions are. Just as the Romans have
adapted Christianity to strengthen their Empire, so is Islam being used to
gain power to the Arabs.</p>

]]></content>
	
  </entry>
	
  <entry>
	<title>Vocabulary</title>
    <link href="http://islamtruth.org/islam/vocab/"/>
	<id>http://islamtruth.org/islam/vocab/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>As islam is heavily based on the arabic language, which is not widely known
outside of islam countries, I have listed a few of the slang that muslims
would be familiar with. Note that this is just a very small selection of
words, there is a lot more.</p>

<blockquote>
    
<style>
div.dictionary p {
    padding-left: 1em !important;
    text-indent: -1em !important;
    margin: 0px !important;
}
</style>

<div class="dictionary is-size-7 has-text-justified">
    <p><strong>Adhan</strong>: The call to prayer which is said in Arabic at the start of the
prayer time interval.</p>

<p><strong>Allah</strong>: The Arabic term for “God.”</p>

<p><strong>As-salaam alaikum</strong>: A common greeting used by Muslims around the world which
means “peace be upon you” in Arabic. The response is wa-alaikum as-salaam, “may
peace be upon you too.”</p>

<p><strong>Dhimmi</strong>: A non-muslim person living in muslim territory that is tolerated
because he/she is paying <em>jizya</em>.</p>

<p><strong>Fasiq</strong>: Someone who violates islamic law. Their testimony in islamic court
is not admissible.</p>

<p><strong>Fatwa</strong>: a religious <em>opinion</em> or <em>ruling</em>. Sometimes used to issue death
rulings to people who oppose Islamic teachings. Sometimes these result in
people having to go into police protection.</p>

<p><strong>Hadith</strong>: Sayings or actions of the Prophet Muhammad that were recorded by
his companions and later collected and preserved for later generations. They
help to elaborate on certain teachings, beliefs, and verses in the Qur’an.
Different sects of Islam differ in which hadiths they find to be <em>authentic</em>.</p>

<p><strong>Hijab</strong>: Headscarf worn by muslim women.</p>

<p><strong>Imam</strong>: The leader of congregational prayer, or a religious leader.</p>

<p><strong>Islam</strong>: The proper name of the religion which, which means <em>submission</em>
or <em>surrender</em>.</p>

<p><strong>Jizya</strong>: A special tax imposed on non-muslims living in muslim territory.</p>

<p><strong>Jinn</strong>: Islamic version of spirits or demons. They appear in the Qur&rsquo;an a
few times.</p>

<p><strong>Kafir</strong>: a non-believer. Also <em>kufr</em>.</p>

<p><strong>Masjid</strong>: The Arabic word for “mosque,” the house of worship. Often women
are not allowed, or have to use different doors, and are not allowed to pray
in the same room as men.</p>

<p><strong>Muhammad</strong>: The final prophet to whom Muslims believe God revealed the
Qur’an.</p>

<p><strong>Muslim</strong>: A person who follows the religion of Islam. It sounds similar to
the word Islam. This is because both of the words come from the same root s-l-m
which means peace. A Muslim is someone who practices Islam.</p>

<p><strong>Prophet</strong>: A person Muslims believe was chosen by God to teach two core
messages: 1) God alone should be worshiped; and 2) people should strive to live
ethically by treating others as they wish to be treated (The Golden Rule.) Adam
is considered to be the first prophet and Muhammad is the last, with many
others in between, 25 of whom are mentioned by name in the Qur’an, including
well-known biblical figures such as Noah, Abraham, Isaac, Ishmael, Moses, David
and Jesus.</p>

<p><strong>Qur’an</strong>: The Holy Book of Islam, which is believed to be the words of God
that were revealed to the Prophet Muhammad. The word Qur’an literally means
“the recitation.”</p>

<p><strong>Shaytan</strong>: The Islamic version of satan, a creature believe to exist
(invisibly?) tempting humans to commit <em>sins</em>.</p>

<p><strong>Shirk</strong>: The act of worshipping other gods besides Allah.</p>

<p><strong>Sunnah</strong>: The example or practice of the Prophet Muhammad. Much of what is
known about the Sunnah is from the collection of sayings or reports known as
hadith, or prophetic traditions.</p>

<p><strong>Surah</strong>: A chapter of the Qur’an. There are 114 surahs in the Qur’an.</p>

<p><strong>Taghut</strong>: The enemies of Muhammed: people who believe in gods other than
Allah.</p>

</div>


</blockquote>


<p>Sources:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://ing.org/basic-vocabulary-about-muslims-and-their-faith/">https://ing.org/basic-vocabulary-about-muslims-and-their-faith/</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
	
  </entry>
	
  <entry>
	<title>New Site!</title>
    <link href="http://islamtruth.org/post/new-site/"/>
	<id>http://islamtruth.org/post/new-site/</id>
    <published>2018-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p>Hey all,</p>

<p>I just got this new site going. I hope it will receive the warm welcome
it deserves. It&rsquo;s not actually that easy to do all of this stuff, you
know &ndash; researching everything, documenting the sources, finding
images and videos to link to, making everything look pretty. But I think
I&rsquo;m doing a good job. I mean someone has to, the amount of factually
false information on the web is staggering!</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m still thinking of some things. I feel like the site needs some
interactivity. Maybe a chat? Nah, that would just totally escalate.
Same thing with comments. But maybe a mailing list or something
like that?</p>

<p>If you have any ideas, don&rsquo;t hesitate to contact me! I&rsquo;d also appreciate
any and all kinds of help with hosting, translating, writing new content,
or even just if you have any corrections, do send them to me.</p>

<p>Love, Mustafa.</p>

]]></content>
	
  </entry>
	
  <entry>
	<title>401 Unauthorized</title>
    <link href="http://islamtruth.org/401/"/>
	<id>http://islamtruth.org/401/</id>
    <published>2017-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[
<p><em><strong>A user name and password is required.</strong></em></p>

<p>You&rsquo;ve attempted to visit a section of the website reserved for authorized
users.</p>

<p><strong>Hugo-smorg</strong> provides the ability to generated a custom error page. 404 pages
are generated by the default Hugo mechanism; use <code>layout: errorpage</code> in
front-matter to create 401 and other pages as required.</p>

]]></content>
	
  </entry>
	
  <entry>
	<title>Funny</title>
    <link href="http://islamtruth.org/resource/images/"/>
	<id>http://islamtruth.org/resource/images/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[

]]></content>
	
  </entry>
	
  <entry>
	<title>Online</title>
    <link href="http://islamtruth.org/resource/online/"/>
	<id>http://islamtruth.org/resource/online/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[

]]></content>
	
  </entry>
	
  <entry>
	<title>Slavery</title>
    <link href="http://islamtruth.org/controversy/slavery/"/>
	<id>http://islamtruth.org/controversy/slavery/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<content type="html"><![CDATA[

]]></content>
	
  </entry>
	
</feed>
